<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Distributed Systems on iustinian-olaru</title><link>https://olaru.dk/tags/distributed-systems/</link><description>Recent content in Distributed Systems on iustinian-olaru</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olaru.dk/tags/distributed-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://olaru.dk/about_me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://olaru.dk/about_me/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a software engineer and architect with a strong foundation in both practical engineering and research‑driven
analysis. My background spans computer science, bioinformatics, distributed systems, and simulation modeling, giving me
a unique ability to approach software not just as code, but as a system of interconnected constraints, abstractions, and
design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What defines my work is the combination of &lt;strong&gt;deep technical curiosity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;a clear, structured approach to solving
complex problems&lt;/strong&gt;. I am drawn to domains where correctness, maintainability, and conceptual clarity matter—where a
system must not only function today but remain robust and adaptable for years to come. This mindset has guided me
through projects involving message queue architectures, enterprise‑scale data modeling, drone‑based measurement
workflows, financial simulation engines, and scientific analysis pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Feasibility Study of RabbitMQ</title><link>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my internship at Novicell, I was part of the A‑Team, the department responsible for maintaining and developing the solutions for three of Denmark&amp;rsquo;s largest e‑commerce platforms: &lt;strong&gt;Power.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a major consumer electronics retailer), &lt;strong&gt;Biltema.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (one of the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest consumer goods chains), and &lt;strong&gt;Apoteket.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a large national pharmacy platform). These systems experience extreme traffic spikes during events such as Black Friday and the Christmas shopping season. To support the scalability demands of these high‑throughput environments, I was tasked with a structured, scientific investigation into whether &lt;strong&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/strong&gt; could serve as a reliable core technology for message processing and load distribution. The goal was to determine its architectural suitability and ensure that the company&amp;rsquo;s systems could handle peak seasonal workloads without service degradation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>