<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on iustinian-olaru</title>
    <link>https://olaru.dk/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on iustinian-olaru</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://olaru.dk/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation projects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://olaru.dk/projects/experiment-orchestration-app/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment Project at the Cognition and Behavior Laboratory in Aarhus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : An independent project aimed at testing heart rate synchronization during shared activities, utilizing Wii remotes and biometric data collection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-monitoring-framework/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message Queue System Framework at Novicell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Developed a RabbitMQ message system library for an API during a second internship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://olaru.dk/projects/flight-assistant/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flight Assistant Project at QuadSat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Combined a drone and payload with a Python-based desktop application and AWS-backed serverless cloud solution for satellite companies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drone Flight Assistant App</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/flight-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/flight-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After completing my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, I transitioned from part‑time developer to full‑time Lead Software Engineer at QuadSat, a small but highly specialized company combining drone technology with RF measurement systems for satellite antenna testing. With only five employees at the time, I became responsible for architecting and implementing a new desktop application—later named the &lt;em&gt;Flight Assistant&lt;/em&gt;—designed to support technicians in the field. The goal of the application was to provide a unified tool for configuring drone flight paths, processing RF measurement data from a proprietary payload, and synchronizing telemetry from both the drone and a GPS base station.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MasSpec Data Analysis Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/masspec-data-analysis-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/masspec-data-analysis-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my Master&amp;rsquo;s studies, I conducted an independent research project focused on one of the foundational challenges in modern computational biology: enabling reproducible and transparent data analysis workflows. In fields such as mass spectrometry–based proteomics, research papers often present conclusions without offering a practical way to reproduce the computational pipeline that produced those results. This creates a barrier for validation, peer review, and scientific progress. My project explored how open‑source technologies could address this gap by implementing a reusable, reproducible data analysis pipeline designed specifically for proteomics data, with an emphasis on mass spectrometry datasets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
