<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on iustinian-olaru</title>
    <link>https://olaru.dk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on iustinian-olaru</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://olaru.dk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/about_me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a software engineer and architect with a strong foundation in both practical engineering and research‑driven&#xA;analysis. My background spans computer science, bioinformatics, distributed systems, and simulation modeling, giving me&#xA;a unique ability to approach software not just as code, but as a system of interconnected constraints, abstractions, and&#xA;design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What defines my work is the combination of &lt;strong&gt;deep technical curiosity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;a clear, structured approach to solving&#xA;complex problems&lt;/strong&gt;. I am drawn to domains where correctness, maintainability, and conceptual clarity matter—where a&#xA;system must not only function today but remain robust and adaptable for years to come. This mindset has guided me&#xA;through projects involving message queue architectures, enterprise‑scale data modeling, drone‑based measurement&#xA;workflows, financial simulation engines, and scientific analysis pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>name</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iustinian Olaru&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>roles</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software Developer, Freelancer, Consultant&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I build systems the way I investigate them: with a &lt;strong&gt;scientific mindset&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;measurable outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;, and an &lt;strong&gt;honest account of constraints&lt;/strong&gt;. My work sits at the intersection of software engineering and research, where rigor, clarity, and reproducibility matter as much as delivery speed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evidence over assumptions.&lt;/strong&gt; I approach problems with structured inquiry—baselining, testing, and validating before I decide. Whether evaluating RabbitMQ at scale or extending a proteomics pipeline for PTMs, I let data guide architecture and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>domains</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/domains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Full Stack, NoJs, Open Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>experience</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;6+ years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>location</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fyn, Denmark&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>primary stack</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/primary_stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/primary_stack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;C#/.NET&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>auxilary stacks</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/hero/auxilary_stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/hero/auxilary_stacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python, Hugo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SaaS Platform for Financial Workflows</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/blazor-saas-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/blazor-saas-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project began as an entrepreneurial collaboration with a former colleague who worked closely with small and micro‑businesses as an accountant. Through his experience, he observed a consistent gap in the market: individuals, one‑person companies, and small enterprises lacked access to high‑quality financial and accounting tools that matched the robustness of enterprise‑grade software, yet at a price point they could afford. We set out to build a SaaS platform that delivered the same—or better—quality of functionality and engineering excellence typically reserved for large organizations, while keeping operational costs extraordinarily low. The platform was developed end‑to‑end using C# and Blazor, designed to support modern accounting workflows with the reliability, clarity, and extensibility expected of professionally engineered systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Process Modeling Platform</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/enterprisel-data-workbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/enterprisel-data-workbench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my time at Ramboll, I worked closely with the team responsible for maintaining a decade‑old Python/Django risk management platform used across several business units. Over the years, the system had accumulated significant technical debt, with inconsistent modules, tightly coupled logic, and architectural limitations inherent to the framework and language. As new enterprise‑level requirements emerged, it became increasingly clear that the legacy platform could no longer support scalable, type‑safe, and maintainable domain modeling. In response, leadership approved a greenfield initiative—internally referred to as the &lt;em&gt;Data Workbench&lt;/em&gt;—aimed at building a modern enterprise process‑modeling platform informed by the lessons learned from maintaining the legacy codebase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ Monitoring Framework</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-monitoring-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-monitoring-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my second internship at Novicell, I identified a significant tooling gap while conducting my earlier feasibility study on RabbitMQ for high‑throughput e‑commerce workloads. Although the .NET ecosystem offered mature libraries for publishing and consuming messages, it lacked a dedicated C# framework for &lt;strong&gt;real‑time monitoring of RabbitMQ cluster health&lt;/strong&gt;. Given the operational demands of Novicell&amp;rsquo;s A‑Team—responsible for platforms such as Power.dk, Biltema.dk, and Apoteket.dk—I proposed a focused project to design a lightweight, read‑only monitoring library capable of providing developers with live insights into RabbitMQ cluster metrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Study of RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my internship at Novicell, I was part of the A‑Team, the department responsible for maintaining and developing the solutions for three of Denmark&amp;rsquo;s largest e‑commerce platforms: &lt;strong&gt;Power.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a major consumer electronics retailer), &lt;strong&gt;Biltema.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (one of the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest consumer goods chains), and &lt;strong&gt;Apoteket.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a large national pharmacy platform). These systems experience extreme traffic spikes during events such as Black Friday and the Christmas shopping season. To support the scalability demands of these high‑throughput environments, I was tasked with a structured, scientific investigation into whether &lt;strong&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/strong&gt; could serve as a reliable core technology for message processing and load distribution. The goal was to determine its architectural suitability and ensure that the company&amp;rsquo;s systems could handle peak seasonal workloads without service degradation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drone Flight Assistant App</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/flight-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/flight-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After completing my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, I transitioned from part‑time developer to full‑time Lead Software Engineer at QuadSat, a small but highly specialized company combining drone technology with RF measurement systems for satellite antenna testing. With only five employees at the time, I became responsible for architecting and implementing a new desktop application—later named the &lt;em&gt;Flight Assistant&lt;/em&gt;—designed to support technicians in the field. The goal of the application was to provide a unified tool for configuring drone flight paths, processing RF measurement data from a proprietary payload, and synchronizing telemetry from both the drone and a GPS base station.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Rule‑Based Simulation Modeling</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/rule-based-simulation-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/rule-based-simulation-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my Master’s studies in Bioinformatics, I undertook an independent research project exploring the use of rule‑based simulation tools for modeling biological and biochemical processes. Motivated by a long‑standing interest in simulation modeling and its potential for understanding dynamic natural systems, I chose to investigate &lt;strong&gt;BioNetGen&lt;/strong&gt;, a specialized framework for defining and executing rule‑based biomolecular models. The purpose of this project was not to validate specific biological hypotheses, but to evaluate the practicality, usability, and methodological strengths of BioNetGen from the perspective of both a software engineer and a researcher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MasSpec Data Analysis Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/masspec-data-analysis-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/masspec-data-analysis-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my Master&amp;rsquo;s studies, I conducted an independent research project focused on one of the foundational challenges in modern computational biology: enabling reproducible and transparent data analysis workflows. In fields such as mass spectrometry–based proteomics, research papers often present conclusions without offering a practical way to reproduce the computational pipeline that produced those results. This creates a barrier for validation, peer review, and scientific progress. My project explored how open‑source technologies could address this gap by implementing a reusable, reproducible data analysis pipeline designed specifically for proteomics data, with an emphasis on mass spectrometry datasets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiment Orchestration App</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/projects/experiment-orchestration-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/projects/experiment-orchestration-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of my internship at the Cognition and Behavior Laboratory in Aarhus, I was tasked with developing a software solution to test the hypothesis that people&amp;rsquo;s heart rates synchronize during shared activities. The project involved participants engaging in both a game and a vocal task, with the aim of capturing synchronized biometric data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://olaru.dk/images/experiment-orchestration-app/heartrate_setup.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Experiment Setup&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and Technical Hurdles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the key challenges was ensuring real-time data synchronization across multiple streams—heart rate monitors, Wii remotes, and audio recordings. The technology stack, which included C# and WPF, wasn&amp;rsquo;t inherently designed for high-throughput, low-latency applications, so I had to get creative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tagline</title>
      <link>https://olaru.dk/tagline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://olaru.dk/tagline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure first. Design simply. Automate responsibly. Document clearly. Share generously.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
