<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on iustinian-olaru</title>
    <link>http://localhost:38583/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on iustinian-olaru</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:38583/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SaaS Platform for Financial Workflows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:38583/projects/blazor-saas-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:38583/projects/blazor-saas-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project began as an entrepreneurial collaboration with a former colleague who worked closely with small and micro‑businesses as an accountant. Through his experience, he observed a consistent gap in the market: individuals, one‑person companies, and small enterprises lacked access to high‑quality financial and accounting tools that matched the robustness of enterprise‑grade software, yet at a price point they could afford. We set out to build a SaaS platform that delivered the same—or better—quality of functionality and engineering excellence typically reserved for large organizations, while keeping operational costs extraordinarily low. The platform was developed end‑to‑end using C# and Blazor, designed to support modern accounting workflows with the reliability, clarity, and extensibility expected of professionally engineered systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Study of RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>http://localhost:38583/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:38583/projects/rabbitmq-feasibility-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my internship at Novicell, I was part of the A‑Team, the department responsible for maintaining and developing the solutions for three of Denmark&amp;rsquo;s largest e‑commerce platforms: &lt;strong&gt;Power.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a major consumer electronics retailer), &lt;strong&gt;Biltema.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (one of the country&amp;rsquo;s biggest consumer goods chains), and &lt;strong&gt;Apoteket.dk&lt;/strong&gt; (a large national pharmacy platform). These systems experience extreme traffic spikes during events such as Black Friday and the Christmas shopping season. To support the scalability demands of these high‑throughput environments, I was tasked with a structured, scientific investigation into whether &lt;strong&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/strong&gt; could serve as a reliable core technology for message processing and load distribution. The goal was to determine its architectural suitability and ensure that the company&amp;rsquo;s systems could handle peak seasonal workloads without service degradation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
